

Vibhor Tambat

Senior Software Development Engineer

My interest in Software Development stems from my passion for problem-solving. Have a long track record of creating dynamic, rich, and interactive web experiences, providing long term architectural solutions for front-end problems on various devices and platforms, adapting to cloud solutions to scale, and directing complex projects from concepts to fully functioning deliverables. Well versed in agile software development methodology. I'd love to be a part of an industry where I get to implement my knowledge and skills and be also learning along the way.

- ★ tambatvibhor@gmail.com
- Gurgaon
- in linkedin.com/in/vibhor-tambat-782203128
- github.com/webor

SKILLS

JavaScript

React

Node.js

Firebase

GIT

Webpack -5

HTML/HTML 5

CSS/CSS-3

JSON

Python 3

Angular JS

Backbone.js

Typescript

Progressive Web App

React Native + Expo

AWS

- www.binarylogic.in
 - twitter.com/vibhortambat

WORK EXPERIENCES

Senior Software Development Engineer Technogram Solutions

08/2018 - Present

Gurgaon, India

Travel Domain Startup

Tasks

- Responsible for delivering Notifications System, Bulk Downloads, Whitelabel Solution. Implemented AWS SQS, SNS, Cloudwatch and S3.
- Created PWA incorporating best in practice caching strategies integrated web push notifications using Firebase.
- Worked on Admin, Mid Office dashboard modules solely created a Form Component Library with different views incorporated Rules Engine and validations which helped in creating 70+ screens in two months time
- Worked on Access control Module using a node middleware used to transpose data and filtering responses. This helped to create global Rest Api's and helped in providing access controls feature.
- Created TGS App (Andorid + ios) using React Native+ Expo .
 Integrating Web Views as different products

Associate FrontEnd Engineering L-2 Avizva Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

08/2017 - 08/2018

Gurgaon India

Web Application Services

Tasks

- Worked On EBMS Web Application. Involved in Technical designs for JSON and Flow creation using Business Requirement Document. Created Generic reusable components using react higher-order composition. Development Using React, ReactRedux, Redux, Webpack for module bundling.
- Associate FrontEnd Engineering L-1
 Avizva Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

07/2016 - 08/2017

Gurgaon, India

INTERESTS

Gym Books Travel Chess

EDUCATION

Maulana Azad National Institute of Technology Bachelor of Technology

2012 - 2016